1
00:00:01,522 --> 00:00:03,921
[Liao-Fan]: My father passed away when I was young,

2
00:00:04,236 --> 00:00:08,157
 and mother persuaded me to learn medicine instead of becoming a scholar. 

3
00:00:08,315 --> 00:00:09,563
Mother said to me:

4
00:00:09,672 --> 00:00:13,421
[Mother]: Learning medicine will be a good way to support yourself 

5
00:00:13,736 --> 00:00:15,552
and also to help others.

6
00:00:15,932 --> 00:00:21,432
Besides, having a skill on hand, you will never have to worry about making a living,

7
00:00:21,722 --> 00:00:25,458
 and you can even become famous through your medical skills.

8
00:00:25,695 --> 00:00:29,616
This has always been an ambition your father had for you.

9
00:00:29,853 --> 00:00:32,566
[Liao-Fan]: One day, at the Compassionate Cloud Temple,

10
00:00:32,675 --> 00:00:37,474
I met an elderly but distinguished looking man who had a long beard 

11
00:00:37,680 --> 00:00:42,280
and had such a look of a sage that I immediately paid my respects to him.

12
00:00:42,378 --> 00:00:44,126
 The old man told me:

13
00:00:44,225 --> 00:00:47,724
[Old Man]: You are destined to become a government official.

14
00:00:48,251 --> 00:00:54,324
You can attain the rank of Erudite First Level Scholar next year, 

15
00:00:54,664 --> 00:00:57,028
why aren't you study for the exam?

16
00:00:57,300 --> 00:01:02,391
[Liao-Fan]: So I told my mother's instructions to give up scholarly study for learning medicine.

17
00:01:02,737 --> 00:01:06,433
Then I asked for his name, birthplace, and residence. 

18
00:01:06,524 --> 00:01:09,324
[Old Man]: He replied: My last name is Kong. 

19
00:01:09,415 --> 00:01:11,869
I came from Yunnan Province.

20
00:01:11,968 --> 00:01:15,367
I have inherited the knowledge of Mr. Shao,

21
00:01:15,677 --> 00:01:18,591
 who developed the art of prediction very well.

22
00:01:18,828 --> 00:01:22,719
By calculations, I'm supposed to pass it on to you.

23
00:01:22,835 --> 00:01:26,755
[Liao-Fan]: Therefore, I led Mr. Kong to my home and told my mother about him.

24
00:01:26,968 --> 00:01:29,622
Mother told me to treat him well and said:

25
00:01:29,877 --> 00:01:35,921
[Mother]: Since Mr. Kong is so good at predicting the future, he must also know our past.

26
00:01:36,248 --> 00:01:39,176
Let's ask him and test his authenticity.

