1
00:00:01,641 --> 00:00:04,175
From NPR News in Washington, I'm Korva Coleman.

2
00:00:04,298 --> 00:00:07,701
Rebel forces in Chad say they've entered the outskirts of the capital

3
00:00:07,736 --> 00:00:10,157
after heavy fighting with government troops.

4
00:00:10,245 --> 00:00:15,333
A French news agency says the sound of intense gunfire can be heard from the city center.

5
00:00:15,526 --> 00:00:23,575
It's being reported that the former colonial power France has requested its nationals gather at three secure locations in the Chadian capital.

6
00:00:23,723 --> 00:00:26,303
NPR's Ofeibea Quist-Arcton reports.

7
00:00:26,449 --> 00:00:30,099
In just a matter of days, Chadian rebels have made a lightning dash 

8
00:00:30,178 --> 00:00:33,420
from the east near the border with Darfur to the capital N'Djamena.

9
00:00:33,661 --> 00:00:37,116
Eyewitnesses reported being able to see rebels infiltrating the city.

10
00:00:37,225 --> 00:00:41,152
A coalition of rebels has vowed to overthrow Chadian President Idriss Deby,

11
00:00:41,231 --> 00:00:45,100
accusing him of mismanagement and squandering the nation's oil wealth.

12
00:00:45,411 --> 00:00:51,346
But there's a suspicion that the rebels backed by neighboring Sudan were sent to prevent the planned deployment

13
00:00:51,429 --> 00:00:58,915
of European peacekeepers to Chad and Central African Republic's volatile border with Darfur, a move which Khartoum opposes.

14
00:00:59,273 --> 00:01:05,789
Chad and Sudan regularly trade accusations that each is harboring and financing the other's rebels.

15
00:01:06,076 --> 00:01:08,552
Ofeibea Quist-Arcton, NPR News, Nairobi.

16
00:01:08,770 --> 00:01:14,751
After-school programs are bracing for a potential budget cuts when the Federal Budget is released on Monday.

17
00:01:15,062 --> 00:01:19,767
Meanwhile, the Education Department is trying to boost the funding for a controversial reading program.

18
00:01:19,985 --> 00:01:22,182
NPR's Larry Abramson reports.

19
00:01:22,539 --> 00:01:25,363
In his State of Union address, the president ask Congress 

20
00:01:25,465 --> 00:01:31,075
to fund 800 million dollars in scholarships so families could enroll their children in after-school programs,

21
00:01:31,156 --> 00:01:33,186
including those run by faith-based groups. 

22
00:01:33,453 --> 00:01:37,739
After-school advocates fear that plan would take federal grants away from their programs

23
00:01:37,795 --> 00:01:41,036
and give the money to recruit the families in the form of vouchers.  

24
00:01:41,394 --> 00:01:45,037
These groups say that would make it impossible to run high quality programs

25
00:01:45,070 --> 00:01:47,306
because they could not count on state funding.

26
00:01:47,547 --> 00:01:53,389
The budget is also expected to call on Congress to bestow more than 600 million dollars in funding to Reading-First,

27
00:01:53,399 --> 00:01:55,340
the special program for young children.

28
00:01:55,605 --> 00:01:58,080
Congress slashed the program's budget last year

29
00:01:58,136 --> 00:02:03,026
 in response to charges that Reading-First is mismanaged and rived with conflicts of interest.

30
00:02:03,430 --> 00:02:05,580
Larry Abramson, NPR News, Washington.

31
00:02:05,775 --> 00:02:13,359
Bad weather in the western United States has closed interstate highways. Recent storms have dumped heavy snow and rain in Northern California.

32
00:02:13,600 --> 00:02:17,654
Two Amtrak trains going through the Donner Pass have gotten stuck.

33
00:02:17,872 --> 00:02:21,462
Some 400 people have been forced to wait while crews clear the track.

34
00:02:21,773 --> 00:02:27,082
Karina Romero was spokeswoman for Amtrak. She says some passengers will spend the night aboard the train.

35
00:02:27,277 --> 00:02:31,312
"It's gonna be overnight, a number of hours. I can't give an exact time.

36
00:02:31,336 --> 00:02:36,973
We will still wait for equipment to arrive on the scene to clear up the incident site." No injuries have been reported.

37
00:02:37,099 --> 00:02:43,127
Authorities in San Francisco are warning the public to avoid water in one reach of San Francisco Bay.

38
00:02:43,229 --> 00:02:50,348
More than two and a half million gallons of partially treated sewage spilled into Richardson Bay this week, an arm of the larger bay.

39
00:02:50,543 --> 00:02:54,295
The sewage is actually from a Marin County Water Treatment Plan.

40
00:02:54,444 --> 00:02:56,680
Authorities blamed operator error. 

41
00:02:57,370 --> 00:02:59,543
You are listening to NPR News in Washington.

42
00:03:01,038 --> 00:03:06,509
As many as 99 people are believed to have died in two suicide bombings yesterday in Baghdad.  

43
00:03:06,727 --> 00:03:13,568
Police say two female suicide bombers were wearing explosive vests then went off in two crowded markets in the capital.

44
00:03:13,809 --> 00:03:17,028
Iraq's Prime Minister says security will be improved.

45
00:03:17,153 --> 00:03:22,345
The bombings have been denounced by the Iraqi government and by Secretary of State Condoleezza Rice.

46
00:03:22,772 --> 00:03:27,407
The unpredictable stock market rallied Friday to close out a strongly positive week

47
00:03:27,439 --> 00:03:31,819
in which the Federal Reserve cut interest rates for the second time in eight days.

48
00:03:31,967 --> 00:03:34,811
Steve Beckner of Market News International reports.

49
00:03:34,957 --> 00:03:39,853
A Labor Department report that jobs fell for the first time in four and a half years last month 

50
00:03:39,955 --> 00:03:42,291
did not seem to bode well for Wall Street. 

51
00:03:42,509 --> 00:03:45,187
But recession worries were partially assuaged

52
00:03:45,188 --> 00:03:51,509
by a stronger-than-expected purchasing managers survey in manufacturing and an uptaking consumer sentiment.

53
00:03:51,797 --> 00:03:56,850
Investors also drew encouragement from Microsoft's huge buyout bid for Yahoo

54
00:03:56,975 --> 00:04:00,054
and hopes for a bailout of strained bond and insurance firms.

55
00:04:00,505 --> 00:04:04,536
With three stocks rising for everyone that fell on the New York Stock Exchange,

56
00:04:04,731 --> 00:04:08,437
the Dow Jones Industrial Average rose almost three quarters of a percent, 

57
00:04:08,608 --> 00:04:11,664
while the NASDAQ COMPOSITE rose nearly a four-percent,

58
00:04:11,766 --> 00:04:15,728
and the Standard & Poor's 500 climbed close to one and a quarter percent.

59
00:04:15,969 --> 00:04:21,672
For the week, the Dow was up 4.4, the S&P 4.9, and the NASDAQ 3.8 percent.

60
00:04:21,960 --> 00:04:23,762
For NPR News, I'm Steve Beckner.

61
00:04:23,934 --> 00:04:28,154
The Senate is scheduled to vote Monday on a proposed economic stimulus package. 

62
00:04:28,229 --> 00:04:33,236
One version has already passed the House Representatives and has the support of the President Bush.

63
00:04:33,384 --> 00:04:37,392
Some Democratic leaders want to expand some of the package benefits, 

64
00:04:37,471 --> 00:04:41,757
such as making unemployment benefits last longer for jobless Americans. 

65
00:04:42,301 --> 00:04:44,985
I'm Korva Coleman, NPR News, in Washington.

66
00:04:46,364 --> 00:04:46,487
 

