[00:00.64]
[00:02.06]
[00:07.13]
[00:08.96]
[00:11.63]
[00:14.71]
[00:17.43]
[00:19.75]
[00:24.02]
[00:26.93]
[00:30.29]
[00:33.13]
[00:34.06]
[00:36.87]
[00:42.46]
[00:44.81]
[00:48.80]
[00:51.82]
[00:57.74]
[01:03.27]
[01:06.14]
