[00:00.18]
[00:02.73]
[00:04.40]
[00:10.05]
[00:13.53]
[00:17.48]
[00:23.19]
[00:27.74]
[00:33.13]
[00:35.08]
[00:36.56]
[00:42.32]
[00:48.43]
[00:52.61]
[00:57.23]
[01:01.85]
[01:07.58]
